<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research | Anthony Schmidt</title>
    <link>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/tags/research/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Research</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/tags/research/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science Education to the Rescue? Assessing The Relationship Between Scientific Literacy and Carbon Emissions</title>
      <link>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/project/dissertation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/project/dissertation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schmidt, A. (2022). Science Education to the Rescue? Assessing The Relationship Between Scientific Literacy and Carbon Emissions. [Doctoral dissertation, University of Tennessee, Knoxville]. &lt;a href=&#34;https://trace.tennessee.edu/utk_graddiss/7303/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://trace.tennessee.edu/utk_graddiss/7303/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a summary of my PhD dissertation. Use the links above to view the code and read the manuscript.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human activities have radically changed the climate, negatively impacting all life on earth. The technical means to address this climate crisis exist, but there are major social and political hurdles that stand in the way. Education has been touted as one possible means for helping to move forward necessary action on climate change. A hybrid model of planned behavior and human capital helps explain how education can affect climate change. The current dissertation sought to assess what relationship may exist between changes in per capita carbon emissions and science education as measured by the Programme for International Student Achievement (PISA).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Results from multilevel growth models showed that countries with higher scientific literacy scores are significantly associated with higher CO2 per capita, though this is likely driven by economics and not directly by education. There were no significant relationships between changes in scientific literacy within a country and changes in that country’s emissions. This suggests evidence for the effect of science education is undetermined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on this research, it is suggested that shifts in educational policies and practices that emphasizes and integrates science and climate change education across the curricula may have a greater effect on emissions. In addition, science and climate education should be imbued with a focus on effective climate change actions that can foster the individual and systemic changes needed to avert a global catastrophe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University air travel and greenhouse gas mitigation: An analysis of higher education climate policies</title>
      <link>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/publication/university-air-travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/publication/university-air-travel/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The representation of women and racial/ethnic minorities in the workforce of minority-serving higher education institutions</title>
      <link>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/publication/msis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/publication/msis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STARS and Stripes: Political and Institutional Factors that Affect Higher Education Sustainability Ratings</title>
      <link>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/project/stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/project/stars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schmidt, A. &amp;amp; Rocconi, L. (2021). STARS and stripes: Political and institutional factors that affect higher education sustainability ratings. &lt;em&gt;EdArXiv&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.35542/osf.io/d5bku&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.35542/osf.io/d5bku&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Environmental issues have played a role in higher education since at least the 1970s, beginning with a focus on sustainability and most recently addressing the climate crisis. Concomitant with the rise in higher education sustainability initiatives have been the rise of higher education sustainability assessments (HESAs), serving as tools for benchmarking, self-assessment, and comparisons. The STARS assessment is the most ubiquitous HESA in North America. The present research employed stakeholder theory to investigate what factors are associated with institutional and political factors affect STARS ratings. Using a multilevel model of local- and state-level variables, the results indicated that measures of local partisanship have little to no influence while state sustainability targets have small effects on STARS ratings. Furthermore, the results reaffirmed past research that indicated institution-level stakeholders (e.g., faculty, students, staff) and institutional characteristics such as finances play a larger and more critical role in institutional sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University air travel and greenhouse gas mitigation: an analysis of higher education climate policies</title>
      <link>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/project/flying-less-document-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/project/flying-less-document-analysis/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schmidt, A. (2022). University air travel and greenhouse gas mitigation: an analysis of higher education climate policies. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Sustainability in Higher Education&lt;/em&gt;, 23(6), 1426-1442. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1108/IJSHE-07-2021-0318&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1108/IJSHE-07-2021-0318&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;purpose&#34;&gt;Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numerous higher education institutions have created policies that aim to reduce their carbon footprints. Most policies focus on reducing greenhouse gas emissions related to energy production and consumption. One area that has received less attention has been greenhouse gas emissions from university air travel. The purpose of this paper is to understand how US higher education institutions address university air travel emissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;design-methodology-approach&#34;&gt;Design/methodology/approach&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The present research used qualitative document analysis to examine the climate policies of 44 doctoral institutions. The analysis sought to establish themes across a range of climate policy documents from the sampled institutions. Intercoder consensus, peer review and member checking were used to increase the reliability and validity of the analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;findings&#34;&gt;Findings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Five major themes emerged from the documents: no consideration of air travel, lack of quality data for accurate consideration, recommendations to offset air travel emissions, support for videoconferencing and other suggestions for mitigation. These themes are discussed in detail, as are practical suggestions and implications stemming from this and related research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-limitations-implications&#34;&gt;Research limitations/implications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The research is based on a sample of US doctoral institutions and their public documents. It is therefore limited in its generalizability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;practical-implications&#34;&gt;Practical implications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Institutions need to create a culture in which individual behavior changes toward lower travel are supported. Though problematic, institutions in the USA need to strive to implement suggested offset programs. Given the ubiquity of virtual presence, institutions need to further support videoconferencing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://edarxiv.org/bmuas/download?format=pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PDF from EdArXiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming Tidyr over Time</title>
      <link>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/project/tidy-tuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/project/tidy-tuesday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project analyzes tweets from the #TidyTuesday hashtag to understand participation and development of data visualization and data science skills.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Intensive English Program (IEP) and Directly-Admitted International Students’ Academic Achievement</title>
      <link>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/project/iep-gpa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/project/iep-gpa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schmidt, A. (2020, June 19). Comparing Intensive English Program  (IEP) and Directly-Admitted International Students’ Academic Achievement. &lt;em&gt;EdArXiv&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.35542/osf.io/vm37t&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.35542/osf.io/vm37t&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intensive English programs (IEPs) exist as an additional pathway into higher education for international students who need additional language support before full matriculation. Despite their long history in higher education, there is little research on the performance of IEP students. The current research examines IEP student performance by comparing them to directly-admitted international students. Results from regression models on first-semester and first-year GPA indicated no significant differences between these two student groups. Follow-up equivalence testing indicated statistical equivalence in several cases. The findings lead to the conclusion that the IEP students perform on par with directly-admitted international students. These findings imply further support for IEPs as alterative pathways to direct admission.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
