<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Employability | Anthony Schmidt</title>
    <link>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/tags/employability/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/tags/employability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Employability</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Employability</title>
      <link>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/tags/employability/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data-Related Jobs for ESM Students</title>
      <link>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/project/esm-data-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/project/esm-data-jobs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an ongoing project to analyze data-related jobs posted on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.higheredjobs.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;HigherEdJobs&lt;/a&gt;. These are jobs a typical ESM student would qualify. The jobs are analyzed in order to understand the skills and competencies that are in demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project is currently focused on administrative-level jobs. Faculty job analyses will be forthcoming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project files can be found on Github &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/acircleda/Data-Jobs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The analyses, always under development, can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://acircleda.github.io/Data-Jobs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fly or Die - The Relationship between Conference Travel, Employability, and the Climate Crisis.</title>
      <link>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/project/fly-or-die-phd-grads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/project/fly-or-die-phd-grads/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Fly or Die&amp;rdquo; project is a multi-survey research project that looks at the complex relationship between graduate student conference travel, employability, and the climate crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Survey One&lt;/strong&gt; focuses on doctoral student employment outcomes, conferences attendance, conference activities, conference types, and publications. Analyses are across disciplines and job industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Survey Two&lt;/strong&gt; focuses on tenure-track faculty search comittees and their attitudes toward recently-graduated PhD students&amp;rsquo; conference attendance, conference activities, and publications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ulitmate goal of this research is to understand the ideal conference and publication record that can maximize employment outcomes while minimizing our carbon footprints.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
