<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Climate Change | Anthony Schmidt</title>
    <link>/tags/climate-change/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/climate-change/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Climate Change</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Climate Change</title>
      <link>/tags/climate-change/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>footprint: Calculate carbon footprints from air travel in R</title>
      <link>/project/footprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/footprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This package was developed with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/KKulma&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dr. Kasia Kulman&lt;/a&gt;. The package started as a simple function and was first featured as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anthonyschmidt.co/post/2020-05-08-emission-calculator-in-r/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;. It is now a fully-developed package on CRAN which allows you to calculate greenhouse gas emissions based on to/from airport codes to latitude and longitude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can install the development version from
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;# install.packages(&amp;quot;remotes&amp;quot;)
remotes::install_github(&amp;quot;acircleda/footprint&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or you can install it from CRAN:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;install.packages(&amp;quot;footprint&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STARS and Stripes: Political and Institutional Factors that Affect Higher Education Sustainability Ratings</title>
      <link>/publication/stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/stars/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University air travel and greenhouse gas mitigation: An analysis of higher education climate policies</title>
      <link>/publication/university-air-travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/university-air-travel/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University Air Travel and GHG Mitigation: Examining Institutional Policies through the Lens of #flyingless</title>
      <link>/talk/2020-11-sustainable-academic-travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/2020-11-sustainable-academic-travel/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do institutional policies have to say about #flyingless?</title>
      <link>/post/what-do-institutional-policies-have-to-say-about-flyingless/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/what-do-institutional-policies-have-to-say-about-flyingless/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This summer, I undertook a small research project that examined institutional policies related to climate change. These mostly included Climate Action Plans and Sustainability Plans, as well as reports, updates, and any other relevant documents available on institutional sustainability websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My focus was on how these policies discussed Scope 3 emissions related to flying (usually termed &amp;ldquo;business air travel&amp;rdquo;). I wanted to see how these policies discussed and addressed the issue of flying in academia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot to say on this subject, and my manuscript for this particular research project is still under development. In the meantime, I have condensed some of the key findings in the one-page summary below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;object data=&#34;one page summary-general.pdf&#34; type=&#34;application/pdf&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;700px&#34;&gt;
    &lt;embed src=&#34;one page summary-general.pdf&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;This browser does not support PDFs. Please download the PDF to view it: &lt;a href=&#34;one page summary-general.pdf&#34;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/embed&gt;
&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Travel Emissions Calculator in R</title>
      <link>/post/2020-05-08-emission-calculator-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-05-08-emission-calculator-in-r/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;link href=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/anchor-sections/anchor-sections.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; /&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/anchor-sections/anchor-sections.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note: this is now a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/acircleda/footprint&#34;&gt;package&lt;/a&gt;! Please visit the link to install and see updated code. It follows the same methodology as below but includes functionality to calculate footprint by latitude and longitude as well as airport codes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am hoping to soon be working with a data set of travel data for which I will need to calculate carbon emissions of flights. There are a number of online calculators, but none that I know of that could be pulled into R to call as a function and or be used to process data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;whats-in-an-emissions-calculator&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What’s in an Emissions Calculator?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I decided to write my own function to do so. The first thing I needed to understand was how carbon emissions for air travel are calculated. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eci.ox.ac.uk/research/energy/downloads/jardine09-carboninflights.pdf&#34;&gt;Dr. Christian Jardine authored a report in 2009 that detailed a number of different carbon emissions calculators&lt;/a&gt;. Nearly all are approximations that cannot account for the specifics of individual trips. However, some are better than others. The best carbon emissions calculators use information available on airplane size, fuel burn, freight weight, passenger capacity, and a number of other factors. Some of that data is proprietary, as is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sabreredappcentre.sabre.com/apps/Carbon-Emission-Calculator&#34;&gt;one of the best calculators offered by Sabre Holdings&lt;/a&gt;. This is one of the best because Sabre produces a reservation system used by airlines and can access the specific data needed for the most accurate emissions calculations. Other calculators, such as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icao.int/environmental-protection/Carbonoffset/Pages/default.aspx&#34;&gt;ICAO calculator&lt;/a&gt;, is public ally available as a web interface for free, but to access the data that underlies the calculations (e.g. the Traffic by Flight Stage database) costs a lot of money. Some models are extremely simple, such as the model offered by the World Resources Institute, which basically uses a flat emissions factor of 0.18 kgCO2/km. This is a crude statistic that cannot account for a number of factors related to airplane emissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, I was able to find the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/greenhouse-gas-reporting-conversion-factors-2019&#34;&gt;UK’s Department for Environment, Food and Rural Affairs (DEFRA)&lt;/a&gt;. They have updated data that is freely available and takes into consideration &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; of the important factors above, and include radiative forcing in their load factors. This is important to include because airplanes inject a number of greenhouse gases directly into the atmosphere and thus their emission act differently than that of cars or electricity generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems to be the best source of loadings to use for an R-based emissions calculator. The downside is that it uses the terminology &lt;em&gt;domestic, short-haul, long-haul&lt;/em&gt;, and *international without clearly defining what they mean in terms of kilometers. Their &lt;a href=&#34;https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/829336/2019_Green-house-gas-reporting-methodology.pdf&#34;&gt;methodology&lt;/a&gt; states that anything within the UK is “domestic”, and that flights up to 3,700km are “short-haul”. “Long haul” is over 3,700km. “International” flights are those entirely outside the UK. It’s not clear if flights within Europe are considered international.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the data I will work with are based in the US, so the UK data introduces some additional uncertainty into my calculations. I did find the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.epa.gov/sites/production/files/2020-04/documents/ghg-emission-factors-hub.pdf&#34;&gt;US Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) emissions calculations&lt;/a&gt;, thinking this would be more US-based, but these are actually based on DEFRA. Interestingly, the EPA reports mileage ranges for short, medium, and long haul flights, but I could not find the corresponding DEFRA data (after converting from miles to kilometers). The EPA also did not separate out their emissions by passenger class, so it was not easy to map mileage distinctions to actual emissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given this small amount of uncertainty, I decided to use the DEFRA data, but EPA mileage instead of the to/from UK distinctions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;header&#34;&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;DEFRA&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;EPA&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Distance&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Domestic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Short-haul&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&amp;lt; 483 km&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Short-haul&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Medium-haul&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;483 &amp;lt; 3,700 km&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Long-haul&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Long-haul&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&amp;gt; 3700 km&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where flight class information was not available, I used data from the prior highest class, and when there were no other classes, I used “average passenger” data and labelled it “unknown”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;working-with-airport-data-in-r&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Working with Airport Data in R&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my research on this project, I found that someone has already made their own calculator in R. &lt;a href=&#34;https://sheilasaia.rbind.io/post/2019-04-19-carbon-cost-calcs/&#34;&gt;Dr. Sheila Saia’s post&lt;/a&gt; introduced me to the &lt;code&gt;airportr&lt;/code&gt; package that can be used to look up airport codes and calculate distance (using &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great-circle_distance&#34;&gt;Great Circle Distance&lt;/a&gt;) automatically in R.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sheila also made a function to automatically calculate emissions. However, their calculator used a flat calculation of 0.24 pounds of CO2 per mile. I wanted to have a more accurate number. What I liked about their calculator was that it also calculated carbon offset cost using the EPA’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://19january2017snapshot.epa.gov/sites/production/files/2016-12/documents/sc_co2_tsd_august_2016.pdf&#34;&gt;Social Cost of Carbon Technical Report&lt;/a&gt; and fit a linear model to make offset recommendations. This is cool, but beyond what I needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;the-calculator&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Calculator&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The model for the calculator I decided to develop is based on the distance from departure airport to arrival airport for one person. It also accounts for flight class (economy, premium economy, business, first), and allows options for different types of metrics (co2e, co2, ch4, n20). If there are multiple legs in the trip, they can be calculated separately and summed. Likewise for round trips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The calculator is not a package but a script which can be &lt;strong&gt;downloaded from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/acircleda/Flight-Emissions-Calculator&#34;&gt;my GithUb repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. It also requires the installation of &lt;code&gt;airportr&lt;/code&gt; package and downloading the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/acircleda/Flight-Emissions-Calculator/blob/master/calculations.RData&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;calculations.RData&lt;/code&gt; file&lt;/a&gt;. The script will load both. The script then uses the &lt;code&gt;emissions&lt;/code&gt; function to calculate emissions based on arrival and departure airports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;examples&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Examples&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calculating distance between LAX and Hong Kong:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;source(&amp;quot;flight emissions calculator.R&amp;quot;)
emissions(&amp;quot;DEN&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;HKK&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Economy&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## [1] 1870.993&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can also calculate distance and add to an existing data frame using &lt;code&gt;mutate&lt;/code&gt; and calculate multiple itineraries at the same time. Here is some example data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;travel_data &amp;lt;- data.frame(name=c(&amp;quot;Mike&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Will&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Elle&amp;quot;),
                          from=c(&amp;quot;LAX&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;LGA&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;TYS&amp;quot;),
                            to=c(&amp;quot;PUS&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;LHR&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;TPA&amp;quot;)
                            )

travel_data %&amp;gt;% 
  knitr::kable()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;header&#34;&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;from&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;to&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Mike&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;LAX&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;PUS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Will&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;LGA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;LHR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Elle&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;TYS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;TPA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how you can take the &lt;code&gt;from&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;to&lt;/code&gt; data and calculate emissions for each trip:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;travel_data %&amp;gt;%
  rowwise() %&amp;gt;%
  mutate(emissions = emissions(from, to, output=&amp;quot;co2&amp;quot;)) %&amp;gt;%
  knitr::kable()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;header&#34;&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;from&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;to&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;emissions&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Mike&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;LAX&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;PUS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1873.3578&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;even&#34;&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Will&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;LGA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;LHR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1077.9199&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;odd&#34;&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Elle&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;TYS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;TPA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;138.9975&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that this calculator is of some use. Feel free to improve it over on Github!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Document Analysis of University Climate Policies and Air Travel</title>
      <link>/project/flying-less-document-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/flying-less-document-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project utilize qualitative document analysis to examine the role of flying less as a Scope 3 emissions reduction strategy in various university climate policies. It will include documents from UTK, &lt;a href=&#34;https://oira.utk.edu/peer-institutions/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UTK peer and aspirational universities&lt;/a&gt;, the top 25 public research universities, and specific institutions that have explicit attention to flying less.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring #flyingless on Twitter with TAGS</title>
      <link>/post/exploring-flying-less-with-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/exploring-flying-less-with-tags/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;I recently started using &lt;a href=&#34;https://tags.hawksey.info/&#34;&gt;TAGS&lt;/a&gt; to start archiving Twitter posts with key search phrases for later exploration and possible research. One of my search phrases was the hashtag #flyingless. #flyingless typically is appended to posts related to reducing the carbon footprint associated with flying, often flying to and from conferences, but also flying in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By just scraping the past few days worth of data, I found a few interesting takeaways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;policies-and-guides&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Policies and Guides&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fundings organizations are taking the carbon footprint of their funds into account. This is from the UK, but maybe we will see similar things from NSF or NIH?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jamesryle/status/1232612369265721345&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1232612369265721345.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Santa Barbara is also promoting smaller carbon footprints with their &lt;a href=&#34;http://hiltner.english.ucsb.edu/index.php/ncnc-guide/&#34;&gt;Nearly Carbon-Neutral Conference Model Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/EINS78/status/1233111821495754752&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1233111821495754752.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;conferences-are-paying-attention&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Conferences Are Paying Attention&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AntoniaSladek/status/1230871054387687424&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1230871054387687424.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sachbon/status/1232408500178956290&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1232408500178956290.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;there-is-some-good-research-about-flyingless&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;There is some good research about #flyingless&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned about &lt;a href=&#34;https://openresearch-repository.anu.edu.au/bitstream/1885/13949/1/Young%20et%20al%20Flights%20of%20Fantasy%202015.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flights of fantasy: A reformulation of the flyers’ dilemma&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Young, M., Markham, F., Reis, A. C., &amp;amp; Higham, J. E. (2015).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;httpstwitter.comTheGroundedProjstatus1233391406820904960&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1233391406820904960.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this master’s thesis by Lisa Jacobson, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.diva-portal.org/smash/get/diva2:1221346/FULLTEXT01.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transforming air travel behavior
in the face of climate change: Incentives and barriers in a Swedish setting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/KA_Nicholas/statuses/1233771519433695232&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1233771519433695232.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;people-are-enjoying-flyingless&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;People are enjoying #flyingless&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are sharing their #flyingless routes and the joy of slow travel. These mostly seem to be from Europe, where they can take advantage of modern rail travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bestdeadends/status/1231234246444015619&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1231234246444015619.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/steinarhoiback/statuses/1231490161739018240&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1231490161739018240.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/SlowTravelStays/statuses/1232347841886072834&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1232347841886072834.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;tags-is-really-cool&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;TAGS is really cool!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The functionality is really great, as it now only scrapes Twitter from the present to the past 7 days, but you can also ask it to scrape every hour until a maximum amount of Tweets is reached (you set the maximum). It also auto-produces a cool interative dashboard you can play with to explore Twitter users and their tweets in the datset. &lt;a href=&#34;https://hawksey.info/tagsexplorer/?key=1CrSy6fhs9x9cadgMLjPJuzfh5C7c5G3_3AMVRiwd1EM&amp;amp;gid=400689247&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Click here to check out the dashboard related to my #flyingless TAGS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are wondering what you can do with all this Twitter data, I highly recommend checking out the online book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tidytextmining.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Text Mining with R&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It’s actually incredibly easy and really fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Crisis Mitigation: Whose Responsibility Is It? - A #TidyTuesday-inspired Essay</title>
      <link>/post/2020-19-02-carbon-crisis-mitigation-whose-responsibility-is-it-a-tidytuesday-inspired-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-19-02-carbon-crisis-mitigation-whose-responsibility-is-it-a-tidytuesday-inspired-essay/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;After a long hiatus, I decided to participate in this week’s #TidyTuesday on Twitter. The data set was from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nu3.de/blogs/nutrition/food-carbon-footprint-index-2018&#34;&gt;nu3.de&lt;/a&gt; and focused on the 2018 carbon footprint of food based on individual country’s consumption of beef, pork, chicken, eggs, nuts, grains, etc. I produced a map of total food-based carbon emissions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;tilemap.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;tilemap.png&#34; alt=&#34;My #TidyTuesday Tilemap&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This small project got me thinking about the United States, its disproportionate contribution to the climate crisis, and how changing our personal habits may have a positive change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the data set, the US is 6th out of over 130 countries in terms of its food-based carbon footprint, and among the different food groups, the largest emissions are due to the consumption of beef.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2020-19-02-carbon-crisis-mitigation-whose-responsibility-is-it-a-tidytuesday-inspired-essay/index_files/figure-html/data-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is beef such a carbon-intensive food? Beef requires more land - land for raising cows and land required to grow the grain to feed them - and more resources overall. According to an article from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.smithsonianmag.com/science-nature/beef-uses-ten-times-more-resources-poultry-dairy-eggs-pork-180952103/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Smithsonian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, “beef requires 28 times more land, six times more fertilizer and 11 times more water compared to those other food sources. That adds up to about five times more greenhouse gas emissions.” In addition, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npr.org/sections/thesalt/2014/04/11/301794415/gassy-cows-are-warming-the-planet-and-theyre-here-to-stay&#34;&gt;methane released from cows&lt;/a&gt; increase the already high carbon footprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This had me wondering: if beef has such a large carbon footprint, what impact would a reduction in beef consumption have? It also led to a deeper question: can individual changes really help mitigate climate change?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;eat-less-beef&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Eat Less Beef?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data above indicates Americans eat 36.24kg of beef per person per year, which equates to 1118.29 kg/CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; per person per year. Of course, this is just the average. Some eat more, some eat less or none at all. According to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.census.gov/popclock/&#34;&gt;US Census Population Clock&lt;/a&gt;, there were 329,302,971 people in the US on February 19, 2020. Let’s trim 5% off of that figure to account for the extremely young and old, and another 4% to account for &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vegetarianism_by_country&#34;&gt;the number of vegetarians and vegans in the us&lt;/a&gt;. That leaves
an estimated beef-consuming US population of 299,665,704 people. Using the emissions figure above, the beef-related emissions of these people equals 335,113,160,126 kg/CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/year, or, &lt;strong&gt;335,113,160 metric tons of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; each year&lt;/strong&gt;. According to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://folk.uio.no/roberan/img/GCB2019/PNG/s15_2019_Top_FF_emitters_abs.png&#34;&gt;Global Carbon Project&lt;/a&gt;, the US emitted 5,400,000,000 metric tons of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in 2018. This means that beef emissions account for 6.2% of total US emissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is 6% of our carbon footprint a big deal? Well, consider that this is just 6% of emissions based solely on &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; food that we eat. In that case, it is quite a bit! So, if we did reduce our beef consumption, what kind of effect would it have?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following chart shows the amount of emissions if we reduce our consumption of beef by 10%, 20%, all the way to 100%. It shows a 10% reduction has a carbon footprint of 5.8%. A 50% reduction of beef consumption equates to our habits contributing only 3.1% of the US carbon footprint. This small percentage is &lt;strong&gt;not negligible&lt;/strong&gt; when you consider that we need to reduce our emissions by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ipcc.ch/2018/10/08/summary-for-policymakers-of-ipcc-special-report-on-global-warming-of-1-5c-approved-by-governments/&#34;&gt;45% overall&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2020-19-02-carbon-crisis-mitigation-whose-responsibility-is-it-a-tidytuesday-inspired-essay/index_files/figure-html/reduction-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;whose-responsibility&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Whose Responsibility?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above indicates that a small change in our eating habits &lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt; make &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; impact on the planet. These hedges are hard not to notice: &lt;em&gt;May&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt;. These reduced impacts assume 1) that everyone will do it, and 2) that individual changes are the root cause of and therefore the solution to the climate crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The EPA says that about 24% of US emissions stem from agriculture (a 50% reduction in beef consumption could reduce that to less than 21%).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, near equal amounts of emissions come from industry and electricity. Within electricity generation, almost 70% is from industry, transportation, or agriculture. In other words, these emissions are not necessarily caused by individual habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.epa.gov/sites/production/files/styles/medium/public/2016-05/global_emissions_sector_2015.png&#34; alt=&#34;Global Greenhouse Emissions by Sector&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Global Greenhouse Emissions by Sector&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.epa.gov/sites/production/files/styles/medium/public/2019-04/total-2019.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;US Greenhouse Emissions of Electricity&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;US Greenhouse Emissions of Electricity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a sense, most emissions are not caused by individuals. Rather, these emissions are generated by government and business. This begs the question of whether it is fair or practical to ask individuals to alter their lifestyle to avert the climate crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we seem to run into an argument that requires mathematical and moral reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;mathematical-reasoning&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Mathematical Reasoning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall that if we reduce our beef consumption by 50%, we also reduce our emissions from 6.2% to 3.1%. Recall, also, that this is from one* single food source*. Reducing other meat products will lead to other emissions reductions and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.accuweather.com/en/weather-news/how-plant-based-diets-can-help-reduce-greenhouse-gas-emissions-by-70-percent/351781&#34;&gt;a shift to a plant-based diet can reduce emissions by 70%&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asking everyone to be a vegetarian is a radical concept. Asking people to &lt;em&gt;reduce&lt;/em&gt; (when financially or physically possible) their meat consumption is not. This small change adds certainly has a positive effect and gets us closer to the target of reducing our emissions by 45% by 2030 to stave off warming over 2 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can make other changes in our energy consumption and travelling habits, too. But, wait, is it fair to ask the average American to “give up” hamburgers, shell out extra money on energy efficient appliances, and stop flying around the world (flying only contributes about 4.5% to anthropogenic climate change)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is this fair when its government and business driving the climate crisis? Also, how is it fair to ask people to make this kind of sacrifice when they know that the people around them will not? Also, how is it fair to ask people to stop doing these ordinary things that have suddenly become dirty and the cause for climate shame?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;moral-reasoning&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Moral Reasoning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For this section, I am drawing heavily on &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10677-019-09995-5&#34;&gt;Peeters et al. (2018)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, as individuals, our contributions are minuscule. However, they are &lt;strong&gt;real&lt;/strong&gt;. One issue is that our individual actions do not directly translate into visible harm and are thought of as future effects and thus easier to disassociate from. However, the climate crisis is not an event in the future, it is already happening: glaciers are melting faster, there are increases in wildfires, storms are intensifying, and low-lying island land is receding. Therefore, our continued contribution as individuals accumulates and exacerbates these issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, even if we make a person change, others may not. This is an inherent dilemma when a problem is caused collectively. The idea is that “No one needs to change until after everyone else changes” (Shue, 1996, p. 112-13). The responsibly gets passed to other people and the solution is undermined by this inaction. The fact is, other people may not change. However, because the climate crisis is both individual- and collectively caused, others’ inaction is no excuse for one’s own inaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reasoning above assumes, others will not change. However, this is not always the case. One’s own individual changes may be mathematically small but can be symbolically profound. That is, our actions serve a symbolic role and can definitely influence others. For example, research has found a clear “neighbor effect” for solar panels, finding that installation of solar panels influences others to do so (&lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10018-019-00239-5&#34;&gt;Kosugi et. al, 2019&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2020/03/climate-change-peer-pressure/605515/&#34;&gt;Frank, 2020&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To that end, raising awareness and advocating for change (at school, at work, among family and friends) is another action that can be taken in addition to personal changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, we still have several other issues to deal with. One is why is it fair to ask people to stop doing the ordinary things they have always done just because these things have suddenly become associated with the climate crisis. First, as Peeters et al. (2018) point out, “The mere fact that many other people engage in an act does not render it harmless” (p. 433). In addition, what we consider ordinary or usual is certainly not so. Take our beef consumption habits. We are sixth in terms of per capita emissions - sixth out of 130 countries. The beef emissions of the United States equate to the same emissions, per capita, as the bottom 17 countries on beef consumption combined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2020-19-02-carbon-crisis-mitigation-whose-responsibility-is-it-a-tidytuesday-inspired-essay/index_files/figure-html/bottom_countries-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our habits - eating beef, jet-setting around the world, hot showers several times a day, joyriding, leaving the lights on - are certainly normal to us, but around the world, they are matter of factly not the norm. The western world contains around 15% of the world’s population, yet has dissproportionatley contributed to the climate crisis through habits it considers ordinary but are in fact unique. These three charts illustrate this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;totalemissions.png&#34; alt=&#34;A Map of Total Emissions&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;A Map of Total Emissions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.viewsoftheworld.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/CarbonEmissionMap_2009.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A Cartogram of Global CO2 Emissions&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;A Cartogram of Global CO2 Emissions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/1/15/World_fossil_carbon_dioxide_emissions_six_top_countries_and_confederations.png&#34; alt=&#34;A Timeline of CO2 Emissions - And Its Largest Contributors&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;A Timeline of CO2 Emissions - And Its Largest Contributors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Peeters et al. (2018) point out, our actions are ordinary in our local contexts, but unusual in a global context. Since the climate crisis is a global crisis, it is imperative to consider this global context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The irony here is that the western world is driving climate change, but the effects will be mostly felt by those whose carbon footprints are dwarfed by our own - countries mainly in the global south.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As George Bush Sr. once &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ipsnews.net/2012/05/us-lifestyle-is-not-up-for-negotiation/&#34;&gt;declared&lt;/a&gt; at the 1992 Earth Summit in Rio de Janeiro, “The American way of life is not up for negotiations. Period.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, if the American way of life is both unusual in the global context and unfairly contributing to the climate crisis, there is a moral imperative that it should be up for “negotiation.” And that negotiation does not really mean any radical individual changes: for those who are financially able, it means a reduction in meat consumption, conservation of energy, carefully considering air travel, and, again when financially feasible, investing in renewable energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A final idea to deal with is the fact that government and business contribute much more to climate change than individuals. How can our personal changes make any effect when industry emits so much, and government is not investing enough in renewables?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, we vote. Choose local, state, and national politicians who have a genuine concern about the crisis. Next, we vote…with out wallets. As consumers, we drive supply and demand. If we can shift our consumer habits - purchasing less beef, purchasing fuel-efficient or EV vehicles, buying renewable energy power blocks from our utilities, taking less flights - we can have a positive effect on industry. They may produce all the fossil fuels, but we burn them (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2018/10/12/17967738/climate-change-consumer-choices-green-renewable-energy&#34;&gt;Del Valle, 2018&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;conclusion&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individual changes can have both practical and symbolic effects. We can make an impact on our national and global carbon footprints while influencing others to do the same. We can advocate for change in government and be conscious consumers. Climate change is a complex problem, and requires solutions from every angle. As individuals, we can make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll leave the last words to Jamieson (2006, cited in Peeters et. al):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must begin from where we are – changing ourselves, changing our leaders, and changing our institutions – but from here we can change the world. Biking instead of driving or choosing the veggieburger rather than the hamburger may seem like small choices, and it may seem that such small choices by such little people barely matter. But ironically, they may be the only thing that matters. For large changes are caused and constituted by small choices. And in the end, however things turn out, it is how we live that gives meaning and significance to our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Your Carbon Footprint with Google Location Data</title>
      <link>/post/2020-02-10-carbon-footprint-google-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-02-10-carbon-footprint-google-data/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Google collects &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of data on us. If you have Google Maps, chances are your location is being tracked, too. Unless, of course, you have it disabled. But, if you don&amp;rsquo;t, you&amp;rsquo;d be surprised by the amount of location data (and its accuracy) contained in your Google Timeline. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/12/19/opinion/location-tracking-cell-phone.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Many worry about Google&amp;rsquo;s tracking&lt;/a&gt;, but for those of us who don&amp;rsquo;t, there is some potential fun we can have with our own data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, we can &lt;strong&gt;estimate&lt;/strong&gt; our carbon emissions. I say &lt;strong&gt;estimate&lt;/strong&gt; because it is not exact and it is likely very difficult to account for (or even remember) all of your trips, who was with you, and how to split your emissions. Was your flight full? How &amp;ldquo;clean&amp;rdquo; was the train? How much of an Uber trip&amp;rsquo;s emissions count for you vs the driver?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are difficult questions, and the real answer is elusive. But, we can come close. Using Google Location data, We can get the date and time of travel, start and end location, the distance traveled, the place, and most importantly, the activity type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow along and I&amp;rsquo;ll show you what I did. It&amp;rsquo;s no doubt imperfect, but for a beginner&amp;rsquo;s effort, I&amp;rsquo;d say it&amp;rsquo;s not too bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;get-your-data&#34;&gt;Get Your Data&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Navigate to &lt;a href=&#34;https://takeout.google.com/?pli=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Takeout&lt;/a&gt;, and first click &amp;ldquo;Deselect all&amp;rdquo; at the right. Then, scroll down to &amp;ldquo;Location History&amp;rdquo; and click on &amp;ldquo;Multiple Formats&amp;rdquo;. Choose JSON and click &amp;ldquo;OK&amp;rdquo;. Check the checkbox and scroll down to the bottom. Select &amp;ldquo;Next step&amp;rdquo;. Here you can export your data once or set a schedule. Click &amp;ldquo;create export&amp;rdquo;. Dependning on the amount of data, the export can take a few minutes (or &amp;ldquo;days&amp;rdquo; as Google claims). I got a year&amp;rsquo;s worth of data in about 3 minutes. Just refresh the page to check on the status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When its ready, download your zip file. Extract your zip file somewhere convenient. Drill into the extracted folder until you find &amp;ldquo;Semantic Location Data&amp;rdquo;. That is what we are after. This will contain a folder for each year and a JSON file for each month in that year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;load-and-process&#34;&gt;Load and Process&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll need at minimum the following packages&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;jsonlite&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;tidyverse&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;lubridate&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;load-data&#34;&gt;Load Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can load your data like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;df &amp;lt;- data.frame(fromJSON(&amp;quot;file location/file&amp;quot;, flatten=TRUE))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JSON comes as a list format. I have no clue how to work with lists. So, I flattened it out to a data frame. I know how to work with those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was going to write a for-loop to process the file list and automatically load the data, but since I was only working with 12 files (2019), I just did it like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;jan2019 &amp;lt;- data.frame(fromJSON(&amp;quot;2019/2019_JANUARY.json&amp;quot;, flatten = TRUE))
feb2019 &amp;lt;- data.frame(fromJSON(&amp;quot;2019/2019_FEBRUARY.json&amp;quot;, flatten = TRUE))
mar2019 &amp;lt;- data.frame(fromJSON(&amp;quot;2019/2019_MARCH.json&amp;quot;, flatten = TRUE))
april2019 &amp;lt;- data.frame(fromJSON(&amp;quot;2019/2019_APRIL.json&amp;quot;, flatten = TRUE))
may2019 &amp;lt;- data.frame(fromJSON(&amp;quot;2019/2019_MAY.json&amp;quot;, flatten = TRUE))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;process-data&#34;&gt;Process Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought I would simply &lt;code&gt;rbind&lt;/code&gt; the data and work with a single large data set, but many files had different numbers of columns, making it difficult to use &lt;code&gt;rbind&lt;/code&gt;. Thankfully, the data sets had the same variable names, so I wrote a function to process the data, selecting the variables I wanted and making a few changes (see &lt;a href=&#34;#function&#34;&gt;below&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;become-familiar-with-the-variables&#34;&gt;Become Familiar with the Variables&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before processing the data, you should become familiar with the column names and what you may want to focus on. There are &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of variables in the JSON file. There are variables for start and end location, path variables, distance, place name, accuracy estimates, etc. Here are the ones I was most interested in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;timelineObjects.activitySegment.distance

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;distance travelled in feet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;timelineObjects.activitySegment.activityType

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;flying, walking, in a car, on a train, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;timelineObjects.activitySegment.startLocation.latitudeE7 and timelineObjects.activitySegment.startLocation.longitudeE7

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;starting location&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;timelineObjects.activitySegment.endLocation.latitudeE7 and timelineObjects.activitySegment.endLocation.longitudeE7

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ending location&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;timelineObjects.placeVisit.location.name

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the place I went to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;timelineObjects.placeVisit.duration.startTimestampMs

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the start time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://shiring.github.io/maps/2016/12/30/Standortverlauf_post&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Shirin&amp;rsquo;s playgRound&lt;/a&gt;, I had some clues about what to process in R, namely:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to convert long/late from IE7 to GPS (divide by &lt;code&gt;1e7&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to convert time from POSIX milliseconds to human readable time &lt;code&gt;as.POSIXct(as.numeric(time_variable)/1000, origin = &amp;quot;1970-01-01&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One problem I noticed was that many rows were offset, meaning data was split between two or three rows. For example, time might have been in row 1 and location, and activity were in the next row. Sometimes, it was three rows. I used &lt;code&gt;lead()&lt;/code&gt; to grab data from the next row, and &lt;code&gt;zoo::na.locf()&lt;/code&gt; to grab data from the last non-empty row when &lt;code&gt;lead()&lt;/code&gt; wouldn&amp;rsquo;t do the trick. This is not a perfect solution and no doubt cause some minor innacurrcies, but for the most part, for such a large data set, it seemed to do the trick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;function&#34;&gt;Select and Mutate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following function selects key variables and then mutates them, creating variables with human-readable names. It also converts the distance to miles and kilometers. You could take it a step further and then select only those variables, dropping the original JSON columns, but I decided to leave them in out of laziness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The function takes a data frame name as its only input.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;##process data function
json_process &amp;lt;- function(dfin){
  dfin %&amp;gt;% select(timelineObjects.activitySegment.distance,
                  timelineObjects.activitySegment.activityType,
                  timelineObjects.activitySegment.startLocation.latitudeE7,
                  timelineObjects.activitySegment.startLocation.longitudeE7,
                  timelineObjects.activitySegment.endLocation.latitudeE7,
                  timelineObjects.activitySegment.endLocation.longitudeE7,
                  timelineObjects.placeVisit.location.name,
                  timelineObjects.placeVisit.duration.startTimestampMs) %&amp;gt;%
    mutate(
      start_lat = timelineObjects.activitySegment.startLocation.latitudeE7 / 1e7,
      star_long = timelineObjects.activitySegment.startLocation.longitudeE7 / 1e7,
      end_lat = timelineObjects.activitySegment.endLocation.latitudeE7 / 1e7,
      end_long = timelineObjects.activitySegment.endLocation.longitudeE7 / 1e7,
      time = lead(as.POSIXct(as.numeric(timelineObjects.placeVisit.duration.startTimestampMs)/1000, origin = &amp;quot;1970-01-01&amp;quot;), 3L),
      year = year(time),
      month = ifelse(is.na(time), month(zoo::na.locf(time)), month(time)),
      activity = ifelse(is.na(timelineObjects.activitySegment.activityType), zoo::na.locf(timelineObjects.activitySegment.activityType), timelineObjects.activitySegment.activityType),
      place = lead(timelineObjects.placeVisit.location.name, 3L),
      miles = timelineObjects.activitySegment.distance/1609,
      km = timelineObjects.activitySegment.distance/1000)
  }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I called the function like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;jan &amp;lt;- json_process(jan2019)
feb &amp;lt;- json_process(feb2019)
mar &amp;lt;- json_process(mar2019)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then combined the data frames:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;data &amp;lt;- rbind(jan, feb, mar, april, may, june, july, aug, sep, oct, nov, dec)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;analyze-and-visualize&#34;&gt;Analyze and Visualize&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you should check what activities are listed in your data:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;data %&amp;gt;% group_by(activity) %&amp;gt;% count
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The activities included FLYING, IN_FERRY, IN_BUS, IN_SUBWAY, etc. However, I focused on only two carbon-emitting activities in my data - those that I could easily account carbon emissions for - and created a small data frame to use for filtering:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;carbon_activities &amp;lt;- data.frame(activity = c(&amp;quot;FLYING&amp;quot;,
                              &amp;quot;IN_PASSENGER_VEHICLE&amp;quot;))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then created a new data frame that dropped missing values, selected only flying and car activities, and then calculated emissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;prep &amp;lt;- data %&amp;gt;% drop_na(activity) %&amp;gt;%
  filter(activity %in% carbon_activities$activity) %&amp;gt;%
  mutate(
    emissions = ifelse(activity == &amp;quot;FLYING&amp;quot;, km*.18, km*.14)
  ) %&amp;gt;% drop_na(emissions)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did I get the figures for emissions? Well, it turns out that calculating carbon emissions from flying is quite difficult. Here are some notes from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icao.int/environmental-protection/Carbonoffset/Pages/default.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ICAO website&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Step 1: Estimation of the aircraft fuel burn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Step 2: Calculation of the passengers&amp;rsquo; fuel burn based on a passenger/freight factor which is derived from RTK data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Step 3: Calculation of seats occupied (assumption: all aircraft are entirely configured with economic seats). Seat occupied = Total seats x Load Factor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Step 4: CO2 emissions per passenger = (Passengers&amp;rsquo; fuel burn x 3.16) / Seat occupied&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note: for flights above 3000 km, CO2 emissions per passenger in premium cabin = 2 x CO2 emissions per passenger in economy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icao.int/environmental-protection/CarbonOffset/Documents/Methodology%20ICAO%20Carbon%20Calculator_v10-2017.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;methodology paper&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;probably&lt;/em&gt; has enough of this information, including numerous tables, to make these calculations. While I intend to make a better attempt at this in the future, using some suggestions from &lt;a href=&#34;https://sheilasaia.rbind.io/post/2019-04-19-carbon-cost-calcs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sheila Saia&lt;/a&gt; I just wanted a rough, liberal estimate of my emissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eci.ox.ac.uk/research/energy/downloads/jardine09-carboninflights.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this paper from the Environmental Change Institute&lt;/a&gt;, which explained several different methods of calculation. The simplest is based on the World Resource Institute&amp;rsquo;s liberal estimate of 0.18 kgCO2/km. I chose this because it was simple to calculate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For driving, I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.carbonfootprint.com/calculator.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this online carbon footprint calculator&lt;/a&gt;. I selected &amp;ldquo;Car&amp;rdquo;, entered in 1000km and my car&amp;rsquo;s average MPG (38MPG - though I often get 40-45 on longer trips), and the result was &amp;ldquo;0.14 metric tons:  1000 km in a petrol vehicle doing 38 mpg (US).&amp;rdquo; That is, 140 kgCO2/1000 km, which is the same as .14 kgCO2/km.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I can visualize the result:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;prep %&amp;gt;%
  group_by(month, activity) %&amp;gt;%
  summarize(sum = sum(emissions)) %&amp;gt;%
  ggplot()+
  geom_bar(aes(x=as.factor(month), y=sum, fill=activity), stat=&amp;quot;identity&amp;quot;)+
  #facet_wrap(~activity, scales=&amp;quot;free&amp;quot;)+
  scale_y_continuous(labels = function(x) format(x, scientific = FALSE))+
  labs(title = &amp;quot;Personal CO2 Emissions from Transportation&amp;quot;,
       caption = &amp;quot;kgC02/km for flights calculated based on liberal WRI estimate: km * .18. \nkgCO2/km for car calculated based on .14kg per 1000km&amp;quot;,
       x = &amp;quot;Month&amp;quot;,
       y = &amp;quot;kgCO2&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://anthonyschmidt.netlify.com/post/2020-02-10-carbon-footprint-google-data/personal-emissions.png&#34; alt=&#34;My Personal Emissions - 2019&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a just a simple example of what one can do with their location data. I will be using my data in an interactive Tableau dashboard that also includes utility usage and will allow me to drill down by month, day, and hour. It will also allow me to compare my 2020 emissions to 2019. &lt;strong&gt;My goal is to have lower emissions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there are a lot of possibilities with Google Location data (for tracking carbon emissions, for making cool visualizations), and even with liberal estimates of kgCO2, you still get a sense of your impact and have a visual goal you can compare against for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fly or Die - The Relationship between Conference Travel, Employability, and the Climate Crisis.</title>
      <link>/project/fly-or-die-phd-grads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/fly-or-die-phd-grads/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Fly or Die&amp;rdquo; project is a multi-survey research project that looks at the complex relationship between graduate student conference travel, employability, and the climate crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Survey One&lt;/strong&gt; focuses on doctoral student employment outcomes, conferences attendance, conference activities, conference types, and publications. Analyses are across disciplines and job industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Survey Two&lt;/strong&gt; focuses on tenure-track faculty search comittees and their attitudes toward recently-graduated PhD students&amp;rsquo; conference attendance, conference activities, and publications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ulitmate goal of this research is to understand the ideal conference and publication record that can maximize employment outcomes while minimizing our carbon footprints.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cost of International Education</title>
      <link>/post/2019-5-10-the-cost-of-international-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2019-5-10-the-cost-of-international-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog post was originally published on my other blog, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.anthonyteacher.com/blog/the-cost-of-international-education&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AnthonyTeacher.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately, I have been thinking about the environmental impact of international education. Given that students travel across the world to study, the CO2 emissions generated from their initial trip, perhaps eventual return, and any trips in between, cannot be ignored.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.grida.no/climate/ipcc/aviation/008.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;According to the IPCC&lt;/a&gt;, aviation contributes about 3.5% to climate change, only set to increase in the future. The exact impact is difficult to ascertain, as it is hard to separate aviation from other anthropogenic impacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is hard to judge the per passenger, per kilometer CO2 emissions, as routes and planes vary.  However, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://calculator.carbonfootprint.com/calculator.aspx?tab=3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Carbon Footprint website offers a calculator&lt;/a&gt;. Since China is the number one country of origin for international students in the United States, example calculations for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.iie.org/en/Research-and-Insights/Open-Doors/Data/International-Students/Leading-Host-Institutions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;leading enrollers of international students in the US&lt;/a&gt; could be as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;University&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Route&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 10pt;&#34;&gt;(on American Airlines)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emissions&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 10pt;&#34;&gt;(in metric tons of CO2)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;New York University&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PEK -&amp;gt; DFW -&amp;gt; JFK&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;1.88&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;University of Southern California&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PEK -&amp;gt; LAX&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;1.41&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Northeastern University&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PEK -&amp;gt; DFW -&amp;gt; BOS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;1.92&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Columbia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PEK -&amp;gt; DFW -&amp;gt; JFK&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;1.88&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Arizona State University&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PEK -&amp;gt; DFW -&amp;gt;  PHX&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;1.76&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Again, keep in mind that these will vary based on originating city/country, destination, and connections. The further away or the more connections, the higher the emissions will be.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Averaging the emissions together, that is 1.77 metric tons of CO2 per student just to enter the university. According to IIE, these universities enroll a total of 76,606 international students. There is no public data easily accessible to find out how many Chinese students they enroll, but since China &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.iie.org/Research-and-Insights/Open-Doors/Data/International-Students/Places-of-Origin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;accounts for 33% of international student enrollment&lt;/a&gt;, let’s guesstimate and say 25,280 students. That makes for about 44,746 metric tons of CO2 to attend university. That seems like a really big impact. You can enter that number into the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.epa.gov/energy/greenhouse-gas-equivalencies-calculator&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;EPA’s Greenhouse Gas Equivalencies Calculator&lt;/a&gt; to get a sense of what that means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;International students are just one example. Other examples include study abroad participants, and even attendance at international (and domestic) conferences (see also here).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am in no way making the argument that international students should not enroll and attend universities in the States (or elsewhere).&lt;/strong&gt; Rather, I am wondering if there are any practical solutions that can be thought of to offset their impact. Specifically, I am wondering if it would be feasible to capture a small percentage of their often enormous tuition payments and use that to either purchase carbon offsets or invest in campus sustainability projects. The rest of this blog post will consider the former.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of carbon offset companies on the internet. These companies use money from purchased offsets to fund different projects. For example, &lt;a href=&#34;https://sustainabletravel.org/utilities/how-is-my-contribution-used-to-offset-my-carbon-emissions/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sustainable Travel International&lt;/a&gt; lists three ways their offsets work: “international conservation carbon reforestation projects; renewable energy projects in the United States, or international renewable energy and energy efficiency projects”.  There has been some &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2011/sep/16/carbon-offset-projects-carbon-emissions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;criticism&lt;/a&gt; of carbon offsets, with some suggesting they are akin to the indulgences of medieval Europe. In other words, they make people feel good about their impact without truly offsetting carbon emissions; rather, they allow “governments and companies in rich countries to offset their emissions through projects in developing countries (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.climatechangenews.com/2018/08/31/withdrawn-un-advert-shows-carbon-offset-scheme-scrapped/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Climate Change News&lt;/a&gt;). This is often through reforestation once a forest has been cut down.  Yet, some offsets do fund renewable energy initiatives or methane capture projects. And, there is some evidence that carbon offsets might work. An article in &lt;a href=&#34;https://esajournals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/fee.1515&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frontiers in Ecology and the Environment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; looks at a small offset program in California and concluded that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Offsets can contribute to climate‐change mitigation, but they can also hinder it if they distract from necessary emissions reductions overall or decrease the feasibility of deep decarbonization. We show that California’s forest offsets – by design – account for a small percentage of emissions reductions but simultaneously provide an important opportunity to supply meaningful carbon sequestration and multiple co‐benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it is important to recognize that offsets are not a true solution but rather a temporary one. If carbon offsets only focus on deforestation and reforestation without actually decreasing emissions, they seem rather pointless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, with their limitations in mind, carbon offsets may be one way to reduce the impact of international education to some extent. How financially feasible is it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sustainabletravel.org/utilities/carbon-calculator/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sustainable Travel International’s carbon calculator&lt;/a&gt; told me that my trip from Beijing to Boston would be 2.7 metric tons and cost around $65 to offset. In terms of out-of-state tuition that international students pay (for example, the average undergraduate international student pays $30,792 [calculated from IPEDS] at a public masters or doctoral university), the cost of a carbon offset like above is just 0.2% of the tuition. Even rounding up to a $100 offset to account for students who travel further or from places that require more connections amounts to 0.3% of the tuition to offset that student’s carbon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think any university administrator would think that is a reasonable amount of money to spend since they are already getting enormous revenue from the higher out-of-state tuition markup. Such offsets can also be captured for study abroad participants’ tuition, and since universities already carefully keep track of travel, it could easily be done for personnel travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why would they want to do this, especially if every penny counts? For one, there is the moral obligation to do what can be done to help halt climate change. But, typically the moral premise is not enough. It may help institutions participate in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sustainabledevelopment.un.org/sdinaction/hesi&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UN’s Higher Education Sustainability Initiative&lt;/a&gt; as well. Having a “green” campus may attract more students or a different type of student. In addition, sustainability could affect future rankings, or current rankings in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aashe.org/news/aashe-releases-the-2018-sustainable-campus-index/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;sustainable campus index&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially, for little money, there could be a positive impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this comes with a number of caveats. First, is that it is important to recognize the limits of carbon offsets (as mentioned above). It may be more beneficial to use the same 0.3% of tuition to help further fund campus-based sustainability projects that mitigate climate change. In fact, it is likely that some institutions already use tuition to fund such projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, individual universities calculating and purchasing carbon offsets may be a moot point as &lt;a href=&#34;https://thepointsguy.com/guide/a-guide-to-airline-carbon-offset-programs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;more airlines already include offsets in their charges&lt;/a&gt;. This might increase in the future as more countries participate in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icao.int/environmental-protection/CORSIA/Pages/default.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Carbon Offsetting and Reduction Scheme for International Aviation&lt;/a&gt; (CORSIA; see also: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/story/airline-emissions-carbon-offsets-travel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Stop Worrying about Buying Carbon Offsets for your Flights&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, it is important to consider the total climate change impact of students, not just their initial trip. Do the students live on-campus or off-campus? Do they walk, bike, take public transportation, or drive to school? I could not find any statistics or information that tell me the habits of most international students. But, let’s take NYU as an example, which enrolls the most international students in the US. It is likely that international students who attend NYU will not drive, as traffic is terrible and public transportation is well-developed for New York City. In addition, it is likely they will not be able to afford a large space to live in, which already decreases their energy usage. It may be that, by the end of the academic year, their carbon emissions end up equal to or less than the average student or resident. If the campus promotes green initiatives, the impact might even be lower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, it’s important to recognize that international education does play a role in contributing to climate change through aviation emissions. One issue is there is very little research on student impacts (domestic, out-of-state, and international; on-campus, off-campus; though there is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uvm.edu/sustain/sites/uvm.edu.sustain/files/uploads/Documents%20Archive/For_Website/Documents_for_Website/Publication%20and%20Resources/ghg_tracking_at_colleges_in_us.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;some research on campus impacts&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sustainability.mit.edu/ghginventory&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;solutions&lt;/a&gt;). One solution proposed is to capture a small percentage of extant student tuition and reallocate that for either carbon offsetting or other sustainability projects. Given the cost of offsetting, this can be done without passing any additional cost to students. For other projects, it is likely they are already being funded through tuition, and these funds could certainly be increased given the pressing issue of climate change, again with no additional cost to the student. &lt;strong&gt;If we deem both international education and the environment important, then we must find some way to reconcile the impact while mitigating further climate change&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
